所以我给你们展示了如何进行绑定安装，现在我们将进入卷。
So I showed you how to do bind mounts,
and now we're going to get into volumes.
好吧这是另一种方法
Okay, so this is the other way to mount in
可以在这些容器之间生存的新文件
new files into this that can
survive between runs of containers.
绑定安装和卷之间的差异是绑定安装实际上是
The difference between bind mounts and
volumes is that bind mounts are literally
只要你的电脑上的文件就会暴露在容器里对吧
just files on your computer that you're
exposing inside of the container, right?
就像我们在这里给你看的
Just like what we showed you here,
the volume
是 Docker 为您管理的东西，它不会暴露在主机上，对吧 ?
is something that Docker manages for you,
it's not exposed on the host, right?
Docker 就像，可以，您创建了这个新卷，这个新的文件系统，
Docker is just like, okay, you've created
this new volume, this new file system, and
我会留的对吧
I'll just keep it, right?
任何你要求的时间我会把它交给你的对吧
And anytime that you ask for it,
I'll hand it back to you, right?
这对数据库很有用，对吧 ?
So this is really useful for
things like database, right?
你可以让蒙戈写这卷的对吧
So you can have Mongo write
to this volume, right?
在蒙哥的容器消失的任何时候
And then any time that the Mongo
container goes away and
回来就能开始读和写同样的卷了
comes back, it'll just start reading and
writing to the same volume.
所以你基本上是在告诉 Docker ，坚持这些文件。
So you're basically telling Docker,
hold onto these files.
这些文件的名称是 Mongo 安装或类似的东西。
And the name of these files is
Mongo mount or something like that.
有道理吗
Does that make sense?
所以，让我们继续吧，我们会在这里制作一个新的目录。
So let's go ahead and,
we'll make a new directory here.
我们将启动一个新项目。
And we'll start a new project.
所以我退出了，我们会把这一卷称为 " 卷 " 。
So I'm out of this, and
we'll call this one volumes.
卡到卷中。
Cd into volumes.
我们会在这里卷进来的
And we're gonna come
over here into volumes.
把这些都关了我不需要
Close all these, cuz I don't need them.
把它关了
And close that.
我们要去做个新文件
And here we're gonna make a new file.
这个叫 index.js 。
This one is gonna be called index.js.
我们会在这里制作一个叫做 Dockerfile的新文件。
And we're gonna make a new
file here called Dockerfile.
惊喜惊喜吧
Surprise, surprise.
我们想做的就是创造最糟糕的数据库
And what we wanna do is we wanna
create the worst database,
我们只会把文件系统作为一个数据库
where we're just gonna use the file
system basically as a database.
当有人点击端点时，我们要做的就是阅读
That anytime someone hits an endpoint,
what we're gonna do is we're going to read
文件，查看文件中的号码，然后将其反馈给用户。
the file, see what the number's inside the
file, and then give it back to the user.
所以，我又给你写了节点代码，所以
So, again,
I wrote the node code for you, so
你不必担心它是什么
you don't necessarily
have to worry what it is.
所以我到这里来卷
So I come down here to volumes.
把所有这些都复制
And just copy all of this.
你不用担心这里的事
You don't have to worry
about anything in here.
不是，这不是 Docker 文件，是 index.js 。
Nope, that's not a Docker file,
that's an index.js.
但为了让你穿过它的文件系统
But just to walk you through it,
fs stands for file system,
路径是节点的路径解析模块。
path is a path resolution
kind of module for node.
我们在说，把它写在这个 data.txt 文件上，好吗 ?
And we're saying,
write it to this data.txt file, okay?
这甚至不是一个网络服务器，对吧 ?
This isn't even a web server, right?
所以这一切都要在集装箱里运行
So all this is gonna do,
it's gonna run this on the Container and
然后就会离开集装箱
then it's gonna exit the container.
所以它要做的就是从数据 .txt中读取
So all it's gonna do is it's
going to read from data.txt,
我们要用体积装进去对吧
which we're going to mount in via volume,
right?
然后再给它加一个
And then it's going to add one to it.
然后它就会记录到它的记录。
And then it's going to console log that.
然后就结束了对吧
And then it's going to finish, right?
所以如果只是在一个短暂的容器里
So if this was just in
an ephemeral container, right,
都是一个，对吧 ?
it would always be one, right?
把它跑了好吧什么都没有
Cuz it would just be run,
okay, nothing's there.
这里有一个出口对吧
Here's one, exit, right?
但我想让它保持状态对吧
But I want it to maintain state, right?
所以我希望它是一个，然后两个，然后三个，然后四个，对吧 ?
So I want it to be one, then two,
then three, then four, right?
所以我们要用音量来完成这个
So we're gonna use the volume
to accomplish that.
有道理吗
Does that make sense?
好的。
Okay.
我们现在要做的就是打开我们的
So what we're gonna do now is
we're gonna open our, Yeah,
我们会在这里制作最简单的 Docker 文件
we're gonna make the simplest
Docker file in the world here,
这是 FROM 节点:12-alpine。
which is FROM node:12-alpine.
不管你想做什么你都可以做什么
Doesn't matter, you can do scratch or
whatever you want.
我要说 COPY chown
I'm gonna say COPY --chown.
不是来自， c-h 拥有。
Not from, c-h own.
node:node./source.
我要说 WORKDIR/src
I'm going to say WORKDIR/src, and
该命令将为节点 index.js。
the command will be node index.js.
这里什么都没有对吧
Nothing new here, right?
简单的小 Docker 文件。
Pretty simple little Docker file.
然后我们现在要做的就是
And then what we're gonna
do now is we're gonna say,
docker build --tag=增量器。
docker build --tag=incrementor.
建造的太棒了
Built, awesome.
Docker 运行增量器。
docker run incrementor.
所以它说，它说找不到文件，写 0 到新文件。
So there it says, it says file not found,
writing 0 to new file.
如果我再做一次你认为会发生什么
Now if I run this again,
what do you think will happen?
>> 将读取它 [INAUDIBLE]。
&gt;&gt; It'll read it [INAUDIBLE].
> > 所以还会保持 0 ，因为我们还没有安装卷，对吧 ?
&gt;&gt; So it's gonna still stay 0 because we
haven't mounted the volume in yet, right?
所以我们一直在运行它会说
So we keep running it, it's going to say,
我找不到什么叫 data.txt 的东西，给你，对吧 ?
I can't find anything called data.txt,
here you go, right?
但我们现在可以做的是，我们可以使用 Docker 运行。
But what we can do now is
we can use Docker run.
如果你还记得我们的 indext
And if you remember
inside of our index.tht,
让我们把这个做个小一点
let's make this a bit smaller for
a second.
我们这里有数据通路对吧
We have the data path here, right?
这就是如何在节点内部读取环境变量的方式。
So this is how you read environmental
variables inside of node.
所以我可以把它修改为一个容量的内部，对吧 ?
So I can modify this to be inside
of a volume somewhere, right?
所以我要说码头跑
So I'm gonna say docker run --,
不是在， --env， right?
not there, --env, right?
这就是我要为环境变量提供食物的方式
So this is how I'm gonna
feed environmental variables
在容器里
into the container.
DATA_PATH=/data/num.txt ， okay ?
DATA_PATH=/data/num.txt, okay?
然后我要说 --安装 type=volume。
Then I'm going to say --mount type=volume.
Src=，就做点什么吧。
Src=, just make something up.
我要给这个增量数据打个电话
I'm gonna call this incrementor data.
只要你能保持一致就可以给它打个电话
As long as you're consistent you
can call it whatever you want.
然后我们会把它储存在数据里，对吧 ?
And then target,
we're gonna store that in /data, right?
这才是真正的音量要装在哪里
So that's where the actual
volume's gonna be mounted right?
我要说的是增量式的对吧
And them I'm gonna say,
incrementor, right?
所以我要去经营这个集装箱
So I'm actually gonna run the container.
所以我之前就在写这个演示。
So I was writing this demo earlier.
但你可以说 Docker 卷列表。
But you can say docker volume list.
天啊我有很多事不是吗
God, I have a lot, don't I?
Docker 卷 rm
docker volume rm
增量数据。
incrementer data.
我认为应该这样做。
I think that should remove it.
好吧既然我来了
Okay, so now if I run it.
我一定是搞错了
I must have gotten the wrong one.
我们去码头吧
Let's do docker volume prune.
那就把我的所有卷都弄走了
That'll get rid of all of my volumes.
天啊我说什么了
Jeez, what did I claim?
我刚买了个 gabyte 回来就好了
Well, I just got a gigabyte back,
so that's neat.
好吧如果我要这样做的话就会说 5个
[LAUGH] All right, so
now if I run this, it's gonna say 5.
我都不知道这个地方了
I don't even know where this anymore.
所以，让我们称之为增量式数据 2。
So, Let's just call this
incrementor data 2.
所以这将会有一个不同的开始，现在它是把 0 写在一个新的文件里。
So this will start a different one, and
now it's saying writing 0 to a new file.
现在我再做一次它会说 01年
And now if I run it again,
it's gonna say 01.
它控制台记录日志并将其递增，对吗 ?
Cuz it console logs it and
then increments it, right?
这就是为什么它会这么说
That's why it says that.
但这就是我们如何在运转之间取得持续的状态，对吧 ?
But that's how we're getting
persistent state between runs, right?
这就是 Docker 会为您管理的所有数据量，对吧 ?
And so this is all volumes of data that
Docker is gonna manage for you, right?
所以这没有暴露给我的主人
So this hasn't exposed to my host.
我想你可以通过主机来检查，对吧 ?
I think you can inspect it via the host,
right?
但这不是为了对吧
But it's not meant to, right?
它只是用于 Docker 容器。
It's meant to be just for
Docker containers.
这就是你的经验法则
So that's kind of your rule of thumb.
如果你有这方面的信息
If you have information that's
really just for the containers and
这不是主机的意思用卷
it's never meant for
the host, use volumes.
始终希望通过绑定安装来进行卷。
Always prefer volumes over bind mounts.
使用卷几乎是更好的主意，使用绑定的唯一原因是
It's almost always a better idea to use
volumes, the only reason to use bind
安装是如果您特别想要某种类型的主机容器交互，
mounts is if you specifically want some
sort of host container interaction,
就像一个 dev 容器，或者我们使用的那个 ngenx 的地方，对吧 ?
like a dev container, or somewhere
like the ngenx one that we use, right?
这就是绑定程序更适用的地方
That's where a bind mount's
more applicable, where it's
主机和 Docker 容器之间的通信类型。
about that kind of communication between
the host and the Docker container.
再次，此处的主要用例是，您将在日志中看到它，对吗 ?
Again, the primary use case here is,
you'll see it with logs, right?
你会让人们把他们的日志写在一个卷上
So you'll have people writing
out their logs to a volume,
那是很常见的用例
that's very common use case for that.
你会在数据库里看到它的人
You'll see it for databases,
where people are keeping their
数据库状态，对，写入卷。
database state, right,
written out to volumes.
有各种不同的方法可以看到这一清单。
There's various different ways
that you can see that manifest.
所以最后三，二，
So the last three, or two,
我们不打算讨论但还有另外两种类型的安装
That we're not gonna talk about, but
there are two other types of mounts.
其中一个叫做临时 Fs，作为名字信仰者，
One of them is called temp Fs,
which as the name belies,
是个临时文件系统对吧
it's a temporary file system, right?
这实际上是一个 Linux 功能。
So this is actually a Linux feature.
因此，这仅适用于 Linux 容器。
So this only applies to Linux containers.
您可以实际安装在临时文件系统中
You can actually mount in
a temporary file system
就会消失在它的尽头
that then disappears at the end of it.
而你这样做的原因是他们会这样做
And the reason that you would do this,
that people like it, is they'll do it for
他们的秘密对吧
their secrets, right?
因此，如果我有访问密码，并且我有数据库连接字符串或
So if I have access password, and
I have a database connection string or
分析键或类似的内容，我将通过临时 Fs 来进行安装，
analytics key or something like that,
I'll mount that in via temp Fs,
这是一个临时安装文件系统的临时 Linux 内核功能。
which is this ephemeral Linux kernel
feature of temporary mounting file system.
所以这就是临时的 F ，你会发现，对于秘密来说，几乎是独家的。
So that's temp Fs, you'll see that for
secrets almost exclusively.
还有一个叫命名管道，或者是 n 个管道。
And there's another one called
named pipes, or n pipe.
我想我也没说过，也有 Windows 的容器，对吧 ?
I guess I haven't talked about it,
there's Windows containers as well, right?
所以我们在 Linux 容器上做了一切
So we've been doing everything
on Linux containers, but
也有 Windows 容器，它们的工作方式不同。
there are also Windows containers,
they work differently.
Windows 容器实际上是完整的 Windows 虚拟化操作系统，
Windows containers are actually full
Windows virtualized operating systems,
对吧 ?
right?
但你只允许把它们当成容器
But you're just allowed to
treat them like containers.
所以如果你有一个完整的数据中心，它是由 Kubernetes 管理的，它们都是
So if you have a whole data center and
it's managed by Kubernetes and they're all
在任何地方都使用容器，您也可以使用 Docker 来管理 Windows 。
using containers everywhere, you can
use Docker to manage Windows as well.
所以有一个特殊的文件系统叫做管道命名管道
And so there is a special file system for
that called named pipes,
您可以将其用于 Windows 容器的其他各种情况。
which you can use for various other
things with Windows containers.
其实我都没使用 Windows 的容器，所以
I've actually never even
used Windows containers, so
我不会再解释的了
I'm not gonna explain any more than that.
但他们在那里，他们存在，如果你想的话，你可以用它们。
But they're out there, they exist,
you can use them if you want to.
好的，有人对卷或绑定安装有任何疑问吗 ?
All right, does anyone have any questions
about volumes or bind mounts, either one?
有道理吗
Make sense?
>> 您说，其中一个主要用例将是共享数据库或
&gt;&gt; You said one of the main use
cases would be a shared database or
一些外部的东西
something that's external.
你会有个用的箱子你想让不同的容器撞击
Would you have a use case where you would
want maybe different containers hitting
在不同实例之间运行共享模拟数据的同一卷 ?
the same volume to get a shared mock data
between different instances running?
> > 我能看出来。
&gt;&gt; I could see that.
我是说那是另一个体积相当有用的东西
I mean, that's another thing that
volumes are quite useful for,
就是如果我有容器 A 和容器 B
is if I have Container A and container B.
他们都是从同一个数据集里读出来的
And they're both reading
from a same dataset,
可以在这两个卷之间共享卷。
a volume can be shared amongst both those.
所以你可以把这两个都装在
And so you can mount those both in.
一个我能想到的愚蠢的例子
A dumb example I can think about that is,
就说我有五种不同的网络服务它们都在运行
let's say I have five different web
services and they're all running.
他们都在注销，我想让原木去一个地方。
And they're all logging out, and
I want the logs to go to one place.
我可以把同样的记录卷安装在他们的五个中对吧
I could mount the same logging
volume into all five of them, right?
这将是实现这一目标的好方法。
And that would be a good
way to accomplish that.
是啊我肯定能看出来
Yeah, I could definitely see that.
或者你有一个服务
Or maybe you have one
service that's writing
记录到已安装的卷，然后您具有日志分析服务，对吗 ?
logs to a mounted volume, and then you
have a log analytic service, right?
那就是从那个看，展示一个好的仪表盘，
And that would be reading from that and
displaying a nice dashboard or
就像这样
something like that.
所以，对这种东西来说，完全有效的用例。
So, yeah, totally valid use case for
that kind of stuff.
是使用卷的好理由。
And a good reason to use volumes.